three of these events you're going to be
moving over distance you got to have
fast feet so to speak so world's
strongest man these athletes have to be
able to move he did exactly what he set
out to do hack is not in your
conversation for powerlifting goat I
think you're doing something wrong for
me the most interesting thing wasn't
even the gym it was the thought process
behind the gym does that make sense it's
like a look into the mind you see the
blueprint like the blueprint in his mind
coming to life very
cool hey folks welcome to another lovely
episode we're a little Pres Sumptuous
there but lovely episode of strength
weekly let's get down to our run of show
first and foremost the 2024 World's
Strongest Man events are revealed Barb
Ben will be bringing you
unprecedented live in person on the
ground coverage next up we didn't even
get to talk about this last week cuz
there was too much going on in the world
of power lifting but John hack misses
his weight cut goes up a weight category
and still comes away with an all time
world record juji mufu the super famous
anabolic acrobat self-styled gives a
tour of his
$5,000 home gym we take you inside and
finally Hunter Henderson who purposely
alternates between bodybuilding and
powerlifting sets her own alltime world
record we talk about that accomplishment
and what she's focused on is a
bodybuilding or powerlifting for the
coming months Phil is it safe to say
that you are one of the top strongman
journalist in the world right now is
that safe to say because I'm gonna say
it yeah I would argue that I would take
any other strongman journalist anytime
anywhere as the number one if not the
top Contender at the very least I mean
my my accuracy in Strongman Competition
predictions is unparalleled and I'm sure
the people in the comments will fully
agree with that well here we go we're
going full heel on strength weekly this
week well let's talk about world's
strongest man we'll Dive Right into a
2024 world strongest man okay this
year's world Strongest Man contest
features 12 events across four days of
action it takes place in Myrtle Beach
South Carolina between May 1st and 5th
that's coming right up at just a couple
weeks away oh my goodness in 2024
Mitchell Hooper the Canadian moose will
attempt to defend his crown but some
former world trest man Champions will be
nipping at his heels including two-time
champ Tom stolman and 2020 champ Alexi
novakov is worth noting that 2019 champ
Martin Lees will not be competing this
year's event and has withdrawn so it
leaves the field a little more wide open
as far as former Champs than it might
otherwise Phil we now know the events
across the competition for both
qualifying stages and finals for this
year's world's strongest man if you
wouldn't mind let talk about the
qualifying stages these are important
yeah for anybody who is uh joining us
for the first time who's unaware of how
World's Strongest Man uh progression
through the full contest goes it's a
5-day contest technically it's 4 days
because they have a rest day in between
so the first two days of competition you
have 30 athletes that are split across
six groups in what is called the
qualifying stage the winner of each
group advances to the finals which
competes on the last two days of
competition after that rest day and then
uh the second and third place finishers
in each group go head-to-head in the
stone off which is one of the events
that we'll get to and that is
essentially they just keep lifting an
atlas Stone back and forth until one
athlete can't do it anymore now the
benefit of going uh of getting second
place in your group is you don't have
what I like to just call Cally as the
initiative which is you don't have to
lift first in the stone off so it's
whoever misses a lift first not whoever
lifts more stones in the stone off so if
David and I are going head-to-head and
he has the initiative I have to lift
first if he lifts five stones and I lift
five stones and I try and go for my
sixth Stone and Miss he does not have to
lift again he advances that's the the
advantage of reward for earning second
place in the qualifying stage so that's
quick wrap of of that so in the
qualifying stage we have the Webster
Stones which you might know as the
nickel stones or the den Stones similar
to that it's a walking Stone competition
you have the deadlift ladder which is a
series of uh progressively heavier
deadlifts that you do for time you have
the S the sandbag steeple chase think of
it as a medley of sorts uh the globe
Viking press that's an overhead press
usually for reps and then you have a
carw walk similar to a yok walk we've
saw that at uh we've seen that in recent
world strongest man competitions before
Evan Singleton has that uh you know left
competition came back had that roaring
win in the car walk back in Sacramento a
couple years back and then of course we
have the stone off as we just mentioned
so that's the qualified stage now Phil
as far as the qualifying stage goes any
of these events stand out to you as
maybe surprises compared to what we've
seen over the last few years of
competition uh so I I wouldn't say any
of them are are surprises usually you
see uh in qualifying stages some amount
of the fundamental movements that are
here like we have an overhead press we
have a deadlift which is a hip hinge we
have the Webster Stones which is a carry
of sorts we see a medley so none of them
are surprising what I am hoping to see
though is in Myrtle Beach it gets really
hot and these competitions usually take
place very early in the morning but
depending on the order of when your
group competes you might be competing at
a point in the day where it is hotter so
if you're at High Noon and you're
competing in the deadlift ladder for
example athletes lost points last year
because the platform had gotten so hot
that they were lifting in socks and they
had to hop off of the platform because
they were burning their feet not because
they were unable to necessarily lift the
weights or lift the weights faster than
to score points so notably I remember I
was there live I remember caka had to
hop off the platform uh because it it
was just too hot to stand on so I'm
hoping that the um that giants live is
going to take precautions for the
athletes that have to compete in the
warmer weather if they're running in a
later qualifying group we're getting a
physics lesson and Insider info on the
game of strongman I do want to point out
before we move on to the finals events
three of these events full half of the
events you're going to be moving over
distance you got to have fast feet so to
speak so you're going to be moving
weight in various capacities but again
over distance and I think that's just
indicative of the fact that a world's
strongest man these athletes have to be
able to move Phil let's move on to the
finals events if athletes make it
through the qualifying stage and they
make the finals let's talk about that
yeah so the way that we lay out on the
qualifying stage if you just map out the
math there's a winner from each group
and then there's a a second place winner
who goes over in the stone so 10
athletes advance to the finals so you
always have 10 athletes who enter the
final stage of the competition where
they will run into six more events three
on each day and they go as follows The
Knack Giants medley the max axle press
The Keg Toss The Rains total body fuel
Conan's wheel the BF goodr tires HD
terrain deadlift and of course the atlas
Stone so as you can see as always the
world's strongest man has a lot of heavy
sponsors and they are going to be
heavily incorporated into the events
yeah we've seen that in the past Knack
uh you know folks had to move objects
containers heavy metal things which
Knack makes right BF Goodrich makes
tires there's going to be a tire
deadlift all that sort of makes sense
rain total body fuel makes uh a
performance drink performance beverage
uh so they're probably not going to be
you know they're going to be branded on
the Conan's wheel somehow but you know
it's probably not going to incorporate
the product directly maybe unless it's
like a pallet of it somehow attached to
the Conan's wheel really interesting I
like seeing the Conan's wheel attached
here it's a grueling event Conan's wheel
it's really you know who can dig deepest
as we see with a lot of events going
last is your is your friend here because
you're kind of able to see how long
competitors have gone and you're going
to be able to see like what you need to
clear which like March you need to clear
and that is mentally a huge Advantage
especially for competitors who you know
are really focused on coming out early
and getting that mental Advantage like
reigning Champion Mitchell Hooper Phil
of these events you know which do you uh
have any surprised you I wouldn't say
that any event again these events I feel
like are fairly Classic Events that
you'll see at most elite strongman
competitions the surprising thing is
that there's no log but there still is
as we were talking about the functional
movements that we usually see in strong
men we do see an overhead event which is
the axle press so in that regard not
every athlete is as strong in the log as
they will be in an axle press so for the
guys that are exceptional in log you
know we're looking at our Bobby Thompson
we're looking at our Luke Stan's like
whether or not they're as strong as they
are on the log as the actual press if
I'm one of those guys I'm disappointed
to see that a log lift is not in the
lineup in either the qualifying or the
final Amazing Phil I do want to say that
next week on strength weekly we're going
to be bringing you some predictions some
actual predictions but just a quick
preview just a very quick preview who do
you think is has the best chance of
taking home this year's world strongest
man title I think if anybody's not
putting their money back on Mitchell
Hooper uh they're probably taking a
riskier bet than they need to now that's
just going off of you know he has only
historically done exceptionally well
since he like found his way in strongman
he has hit like something like 15
podiums in a row or something like that
on top of just winning the Arnold
Classic for the second time I think that
Tom stman two-time reigning champ before
he lost the title to Hooper I think that
that like he will come in aiming to get
his crown back so I expect uh those two
guys to be on the podium at the very
least now the third place or whoever
else is on the podium with them
regardless of that order I think is
where it gets a lot more interesting I'm
I'm putting my money on those two guys
to at least get to the podium and I
would put them in one two uh at this
point who's joining them I think is
really where the tossup is because as we
saw last week Martine Lees and matteas
Kish Kowski both withdrew and they would
have been easily in one of the in the
conversation of who else is going
getting on to the podium so at the time
of this recording we don't actually know
the full lineup the there are still six
originally there were four athletes that
we were expecting to still join the
roster Martins and uh Matos are now out
so there's two more slots that are open
so we're going to see who those slots go
to there's a lot of variables going into
this one that's why I think like you
should tune in you should tune in um I
have covered it for the last several
years and I'm very excited for this
world Strongest Man full preview coming
next week we're going to actually move
on to the world of powerlifting John
hack who is supposed to compete at 90 kg
at the ghost at the wrpf ghost Clash 3
and really wanted to hit a 2400 power
pound power elting total which would be
an alltime world record his weight cut
did not go quite according to plan so he
actually ended up competing at 100
kilograms instead of 90 kilograms body
weight Phil how did he do uh how did he
do uh he did exactly what he set out to
do uh he he said he was going to hit a
2400 kilogram total that's what he did
he just was like you know what I'll just
hit the total that I expected to hit
even if I have to compete in a weight
class above when I've only you a couple
kilos into it it's like if he competed
at a 100 kilos and planned it he had
eight kilos or whatever it was to give
Still Still Still hit it it's worth no
it's still an alltime world record in
the 100 kilogram body weight category
right so John hack moves up a body
weight category still sets the alltime
world record because the alltime world
record he was aiming for in that
bodyweight category was so good it would
be the alltime world record in the
bodyweight category above John hack okay
let's just talk about what he did on the
day all right three for three on the
squat ended with a 365 kilogram squat
two for three on the bench ended with a
22.5 kgr bench press 3 for3 on the
deadlift ending at 426 kg that gives him
1, 143.5 kg for right around 2400 pounds
an all-time world record Phil I'm just
gonna come out and say it this is gonna
be a shorter section because like what
can you say we just want to see John
hack lift he's really in a class of his
own not only in the 90 kilo body weight
category but the 100 kilo body weight
category when it comes to Raw lifting he
might be the powerlifting goat I think I
think that when you talk Ed Cohen
obviously is kind of referred to as a
goat has been for several decades now uh
you look at Jen Thompson right people
talk about her as as a as the goat look
this is debatable right this is this is
fun we goat is a term that's fun because
we get to debate it because like there
is a level of subjectivity there hack is
certainly in the conversation shows no
signs of slowing down is only getting
stronger obviously there are different
federations right there are different
drug testing policies for different
federations and powerlifting there are
different rules wraps versus sleeves raw
and equip it's tough to say but if hack
is not in your conversation for
powerlifting goat I think you're doing
something wrong and rant I I would agree
I think you're 100% doing something
wrong if he's at least not in the
conversation for goat I mean also a
representative of equality in what would
be the greatest of all time is adjusting
to things not necessarily going
according to plan like missing your
weight cut but then competing anyway and
then still hitting the total that you
set like not letting that affect you
still getting still competing at the
level that you expected of yourself and
then scoring an all-time world record
anyway like if that's not part of the
conversation of how the best in the
world can also adjust their mind state
to then compete at the highest level in
a weight class above than what they were
expecting now we we've seen hack compete
at this weight class before but it's not
what he was shooting for but I think
that like if hack's not at least at the
very minimum in the conversation
seriously then that's not a serious
conversation well said that's the real
that's the clip right there Phil okay
let's talk about someone who's a a
serious athlete but doesn't take himself
too seriously how about that for a segue
y'all juji mufu the anabolic acrobat who
went viral years ago right around the
time barbin was getting started maybe a
little bit before for doing crazy things
with weights including the splits on
chairs with an overhead squat position
in his kitchen he used to train out of a
squat rack in his kitchen right he was
the acrobatic bodybuilder the anabolic
acrobat and now well he's in this
full-time uh I believe he worked for a
biotech company for a while went uh
moved over to the content production
space full-time or four or five years
ago I might be right or wrong and has
built himself quite the home gym valued
at around $500,000 half a million
dollars of all the equipment inside and
Coupe from garage gym reviews which is a
sister site and sister brand of barbend
we have the same parrot company joined
juji mufu and Ted what I would argue at
least what I've seen on video is one of
the nicest Home Gyms in existence and I
would I would I would bet it's certainly
up there uh Phil what are some of the
takeaways that you got from this
fantastic tour and we're going to link
we're going to link to that article that
goes into that where you can watch the
full video obviously in the description
the link below so definitely check that
out hopefully it's the video you watch
after this video Phil what are some your
takeaways from this tour of jujimufu's
home gym I had two specific takeaways
that I was like ah those are the that is
also incredibly interesting on top of
the fact that this is an incredibly
expensive and tricked out welld designed
gym uh the first one is it's not a bait
and switch people okay it's a home gym
it's still a home gym now the thing that
I that stuck out to me though is the
plans to potentially make it public now
that is kind of cool because this is a
very sweet gym I would want a Ching at
this gym could I afford a membership to
be determined but that is very cool so
right now it's a home gym but he does
plan on potentially making it public in
the future he was saying that that's in
the works the other thing that I also
really appreciated here was why would
anybody want a gym that expensive like
who needs a gym that expensive even if
you're the antibi acrobat why do you
need 500k in a gym won't any decent
machine for what you're trying to do
work well he was saying that he if he
ever sells it he wants to have resale
value and that got me that made me
chuckle because David I don't know about
you if I was ever in a position to
invest $500,000 into my own personal gym
I think that's just mine forever I don't
know if I'm ever I don't know if i'
would ever consider if I'm in the if I
have that kind of coin I don't think I'm
thinking hm who whom will I give this to
in the future you know what I'm saying
that's a good point Phil but I think he
might be playing 40 chess here right I
think he's thinking resale value because
he's thinking well how do I it's kind of
like upgrading car like I'm not a car
guy right but you know how some people
have like a car and they upgrade to a
sports car as like a lower level sports
car then a higher level sports car and
you keep going up the chain right you
trade it in toward you trade it in
towards something bigger and better I
think what he's thinking here is yeah I
have the Sweet Home JY it could be mine
forever or or if it retains enough of
its value I can use that toward selling
that equipment selling the gym outright
I can use that toward a bigger even an
even bigger and better facility what's
the line you know what's cool a million
dollar gym you know it's even cooler a
billion dollar gym what's that you know
what I'm saying what's that tagline it's
it's from The Social Network like you
know a billion dollars isn't cool you
know what's cool a billion a billion
doll home gym the YouTube video that
breaks the internet the billion doll
home gym it's 17 million square feet a
million dooll gym isn't cool David you
know what's cool a billion doll gym
billion dollar gym juji mufu that's your
billion doll gym billion dollar Mr Beast
juji mufu billion dollar gym no figure
it out figure it out boys but look this
is a really interesting tour I think
this is really cool I think he talks
about opening it up and like if he opens
it up to the public here's the question
does he then build a different home gym
you know I mean this is just like this
is just what I'm thinking again is juji
muu playing 4D chess I don't know but
it's a crazy cool looking facility crazy
cool looking I really like look we can't
even go into it here Cooper did a great
job over at garage G reviews and the
team over at garage J reviews did I'm
biased I love those guys they did a
great job diving into not only what this
was and how impressive it was but like
why John juji muu AKA John call made the
choices he did like why he went with
certain pieces of equipment it wasn't
just all the same company right he
didn't just get like you know one
company to outfit everything he picked
and he chose and he was very specific
and very thoughtful about it this guy is
more than just these viral videos and
being like 230 pounds of RI muscle and
doing you know back flips and all the
and splits and stuff like that right
there's like there's a lot to it and I
think if you are looking at like someone
who's at this high level and who has
these resources what what is their for
me the most interesting thing wasn't
even the gym it was the thought process
behind the gym does that make sense
toally a look into the mind yeah yeah
yeah and and also to see like the layout
as well like where he decided to place
all of the equipment it like the you see
the blueprint like anybody who hasn't
seen that go check out that video you
can see the blueprint of like he the
blueprint in his mind coming to life
it's very cool all right let's move on a
little bit uh Hunter Henderson who
accomplished professional bodybuilder an
accomplished alltime world record holder
P world record holding powerlifter
recently competed at 82.5 kilograms went
five for nine on the day and certainly
did not have the day she hoped or did
not have the competition she hoped at
the wrpf ghost Clash 3 but still came
away with an all-time squat world record
Phil mind taking us through uh the kind
of the tail the tape her lifts at 82.5
kilogram body weight yeah absolutely so
she went two for three in the squat she
hit a 2975 kilo squat to open and then
she hit a world record 311 kgam squat
now that's 6 kilos over the world record
that she previously held so she eclipsed
her own world record in the bench press
she also went uh two for five scoring
155 and then 165 missing 170 on her
final attempt and then in the deadlift
she only got on the board with her first
attempt at 240 kilos for a total of 700
16 kog it's worth noting Hunter
attempted a 32.5 pound squat here right
and uh that would have been the all-time
heaviest
squat non-equipped for a woman it would
have been it would have been it only
April matthysse and Australia's Sarah
rainbow have squatted heavier than
Hunter Henderson's 311 kilograms I love
seeing Hunter Henderson go for the
all-time world record here uh for women
particularly doing so several w classes
below super heavyweight absolutely
phenomenal far in away I mean she Clips
the alltime world record for her body
weight category by six kilos right
that's a heck of a performance we see in
powerlifting records move by one or two
kilos at a time set an all time world
record six kilos is outstanding and
honestly like the courage to go and the
mentality to go for an alltime world
record Squad when you're when you're not
even close to a super heavyweight wow so
Hunter Henderson wins her bodyweight
category actually does not Come Away
with the best lifter award Germany's
Denise Herber had a fantastic
performance especially in the deadlift
21.5 kg deadlift at 75 kilograms body
weight to take just at the very end
snipe that best lifter award from Hunter
Henderson uh Henderson still had a
fantastic day and Phil sorry quick
reactions I don't want to I don't want
to steal your thunder because there's a
very important announcement at the end
of this segment there was so much to
cover in the last two weeks on strength
weekly that the fact that like Herber
should definitely have like is worthy of
her own segment if we had more time for
sure she had an exceptional day like her
deadlift is uh something that you can
like rewatch again and again and like
the grit to get through the grind that
to get to that lockout phenomenal yes
Hunter Henderson you and your coach
don't call for an all-time world record
weight on the bar if there isn't the
confidence that you can hit it so even
though it was missed the fact that they
believe that they could do it several
weight classes below is a nod to like oh
this is in her range so like that's
where it's like going into future
competitions next time she competes
which you know we'll see when that is
we're about to talk about about what her
future looks like but when she does step
on the platform if she's training like
she did for this competition and thinks
that she can hit it like that's a story
unto itself it's a big it's big news
it's a big story um one reason we are
talking about Hunter Henderson and we
may might be biased a little bit toward
her here is because she's a multiport
strength athlete she is a pro
bodybuilder and has confirmed to barbin
that for the foreseeable future she's
actually going to be focusing on
bodybuilding and hoping to qualify for
the 2024 Olympia she will attempt to do
that at the Chicago Pro which is in July
so a fairly quick turnaround we're
talking about three basically three-ish
months three or four months here to turn
around try and qualify at the Chicago
Pro in July for the Olympia later this
year Hunter is one of those rare
athletes that can succeed at the highest
level totally unicorn multiple strength
Sports you know we've seen that like a
few come to mind it used to be more
common you know back in the day you had
in the 50s and 60s you had Tommy Kona
who's Mr Universe bodybuilding and also
an Olympic weightlifting Champion
literally a CH an Olympic champion in
weightlifting right like as strength
Sports have gotten more specialized and
as the bar has gotten raised higher it's
tougher and more difficult to succeed
across strength Sports we've seen a few
athletes do
this Tia clar Tumi comes to mind
obviously CrossFit
goat Olympic level weightlifter right
we've seen that happen we've seen some
athletes make career transitions succeed
in like powerlifting and then move over
to bodybuilding and qualify as Pros
Amanda kohatu comes to mind as someone
who was a very very accomplished
powerlifter switched over to
bodybuilding had um quite a bit of
success Matty forberg someone who had
quite a bit of success in powerlifting
switched over to bodybuilding as a
wellness competitor and did quite well
right we've seen athletes make these
transitions between the strength and
athetic sports especially on the women's
side but not exclusively but hunter
Henderson has gone back and forth and
alternated she hasn't oftentimes we see
athletes switch care switch over to
bodybuilding and they that's what they
they stay with Hunter has gone back and
forth and has made a conscious effort to
go back and forth and succeed across
seasons in both which is really
impressive so she is basically a unicorn
in that regard and that there's really
no one else doing that these days uh at
these at the high level so congrats to
Hunter for a gutsy performance looking
forward to seeing her potentially
qualify for the Olympia later this year
Phil that we've gone through a lot and
our World's Strongest Man preview
week can you believe that yeah we are
getting close to see who is going to the
we got to hold off until we see who the
other athletes they're going to allow to
compete who's going to take those last
six slots that are still open for the
qualifying stage but when we have those
now we got the events uh we're getting
close to showtime and uh it's going to
it's going to be hot not just the
temperature but the competition hot hot
hot folks thanks for tuning in until
next time I'm David Thomas to joined by
Phil bman bringing you all the news you
need to know from around the barbell
game